本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：小松狮      校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第五集
沃尔特  我们已经有了很大的进展
Well, we've come a long way, Walt.
第一轮的治疗已经结束了
Here at the end of round one,
我保持谨慎乐观的态度
I'm going to recommend cautious optimism.
两个月以后
We'll check back in two months,
我们会再看看你身体的反应  重新评估
See how you've responded, reassess,
然后决定你下一步的治疗方案
And decide our next move, if any.
就在你妻子的预产期  对吗
That's right around the time the baby's due, correct?
朝好的方面看吧
Try to think of this as good timing.
你会很会好起来的  会更像从前
You'll start feeling better soon, more like yourself,
头发也会长出来的
And your hair should start to come back.
我已经有点习惯了这种光头造型了
I kind of gotten used to the old cue ball look.
应该说是流线型
I prefer to think of it as streamlined.
对  空气阻力小
Right. Aerodynamic.
不再困惑了吧
No more confusion?
当然不了
Absolutely none.
你们俩最近关系怎么样
How are you two holding up?
我是说  我们都挺忙的  不过
I mean, you know, we're busy, but...
我们处得不错
We're good.
当然
Absolutely.
一切都很好
It's all good.
不用保险支付  对吗
So, we're not going through an insurer. Is that correct?
没错  直接支付
Yes. Direct bill.
现在帮你把帐单打印出来
Just need to print it out for you.
我们不是讨论过会有现付折扣的吗
I thought we had discussed a cash discount.
没错  已经包括在内了
Absolutely. It's included.
提醒你一下
Just a reminder,
我们现在有个付款计划
We do have a payment plan available,
你可能会感兴趣
should you be interested.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那核磁共振怎么样
Then, what about the MRI?
你能给我解释一下
Can you please explain to me
诊断性和探索性的区别吗
the distinction between diagnostic and exploratory?
但是他的医生两个都订了
Yeah, but either way, his doctor ordered it.
当然要包括在内
It should be covered.
我会的  一式三份
You bet I will. Yeah, in triplicate.
很抱歉你没帮上什么忙
Well, I'm sorry you couldn't be of more help, too.
贱人
Bitch.
你和吸烟的人呆过吗
Been around someone who smokes?
医院帐单来了
The hospital bill came.
可真快啊
That was fast.
住院三天  总计一万三
Three-day stay: $13,000 and counting.
能让格雷琴和埃利奥特帮我们承担一点吗
Is this something that Gretchen and Elliott might cover?
我知道那样做你会不乐意  不过
I know it's strictly your domain, but...
我相信他们愿意买单
They will. I'm sure they will.
我来处理
I'll handle it.
-给我塞拉曼加案子最新消息  -死了
- Bring me up to speed on Salamanca. - Dead.
-仅此而已  -完全没错
- Still? - Completely.
好的  很高兴你能来
Okay, then. Well, thanks for stopping by.
最近外面很平静
So things are quiet.
街上没什么人卖冰毒了
Not a lot of crystal on the streets right now.
很好
Good.
这种情况不会持续很久的
That's not going to last.
等着看谁会重振旗鼓
Waiting to see who rallies the roaches now
现在屠库的生意很容易到手
That his turf's up for grabs.
现在还没人接盘吗
No takers so far?
我们不断听到一个名字  海森堡
We keep hearing a name. Heisenberg.
最近几乎抓的小混混都提到这个名字
Lately, pretty much every dime-bagger we come across.
-海森堡  -对
- Heisenberg? - Yeah, I know.
可能他会是下一个大毒枭
Maybe it's a tweaker urban legend.
还是有人在秘密制造
Still, somebody somewhere is cooking
那些我们追查的冰毒
that big blue we keep finding.
无论如何  我们会继续跟进的
Anyway, we'll stay on it.
知道为什么鲨鱼在食物链的顶端吗  汉克
Know why sharks are at the top of the food chain, Hank?
因为它们有三排牙齿
'Cause they have three sets of teeth
能一口咬开任何东西吗
and will take a bite out of anything?
它们追踪上千英里
Some of those suckers travel thousands of miles
只为追捕自己的猎物
In pursuit of their prey.
对  我想我听说过
Yeah, I think I heard that.
你  就是一条大白鲨
You, my friend, are a great white.
觉得阿尔布开克联络处
How does Albuquerque Liaison,
三国边境封锁任务组怎么样
Tri-state Border Interdiction Task Force sound?
听上去像是升职
Like one hell of a promotion.
现在刚开始  我希望你能
As of the 1st, I want you to split your time
同时兼顾这里和埃尔帕索
Between here and El Paso.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
没有我你怎么办  格米
What you gonna do without me, Gomie?
当然是庆祝
Celebrate.
再也不用一周六天看到你这张丑脸了
I won't have to look at your ugly mug six days a week.
我可是智勇双全啊
Hey, buddy, I am the brains and the brawn.
我是全能王
I'm the whole package.
还好没多吃东西  我都要吐了
I'm glad I didn't just eat.
真神奇他的头居然不会卡在门上
I'm surprised his head still fits through the door.
-想吃个饭庆祝下吗  -当然
- Wanna grab lunch? - Hell, yeah.
-因为是你请客  -就这么办
- 'Cause you're buying. - Done.
你们两个傻子到楼下等我
I'll meet you morons downstairs.
别迷路了
Try not to get lost on the way.
请讲  你好  里奇
Hi, Ricky
最近好吗  我好极了
How you doing? Yeah, I'm stoked, too.
当然  那可是埃尔帕索
Yeah, El Paso.
大人物来了
Here's the man.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
沙漠里两个  森林里两个
Hits two in the sand, two in the forest.
然后他说  四个一起上呀
And then he says, "Give me a four."
你吃了豹子胆  居然还敢回来
You got some nerve coming back here.
要么你就是比我想得还傻
Or you're even dumber than I thought.
可能都有吧
Maybe both.
赔给你拖车费  修理费
Balance for the tow, the repairs,
另外还有你大门的损失
And extra for, you know, damages and stuff to the gate,
和厕所
the toilet...
就跟我说的一样
Look, like I said,
我说话算话
My word is my bond.
我把车寄放在这里  你要收多少钱
What would you charge me to store this here?
-150万  -别这样
- A million-five. - Come on, yo.
要么就用你妹妹来抵
Your sister.
兄弟  我是认真的  我得把车停了
Dawg, I'm serious, all right? I got storage needs.
前面刮花了
And I got scratch up front.
我们可以  谈谈价钱
We could, you know, negotiate.
500元
500.
-一个月吗  -一星期
- A month? - A week.
说真的吗
For real?
-回见  -等等
- See ya. - Wait.
别急  冷静点
Just hold on. Just chill.
听起来不错  很可行
Sounds good. Totally doable.
-停在外面  -停在里面
- Outside. - Inside.
-那就算了  -伙计  别这样
- Forget it. - Man, come on.
你的围墙太容易爬进来了
Your fence is too easy to climb.
停在里面  锁门  外加大门的优先使用权
Inside, padlocked, plus gate privileges.
-又要重蹈覆辙吗  -大门进出保留优先权
- Come again? - Gate, in and out, privileges.
租金一月一付  先给钱
Month to month. Cash up front.
停在里面
Inside.
我不认识你  我也不认识杰克
And I don't know you. I don't know Jack.
那辆车卖吗
You selling?
9000块卖给你
I'll let you take it for nine Gs.
那辆呢
What about that one?
开玩笑吧
Serious?
你是叫珍妮  对吗
It's Jane, right?
珍妮  这个地方太棒了
Well, Jane, I gotta say, this place is awesome.
真的吗  不是说套话
Really? Does it inspire awe?
不是  真的很棒
No. I mean, it's great.
就跟我想找的一样  我就这么个意思
Just what I've been looking for. That's what I meant.
我以前有一整栋房子
I had an entire house before,
整幢独立式别墅
Detached and all,
但我对打理草坪
But I was just tired of all the
房屋维护  还有摆设布置厌烦了
Lawn care and upkeep and whatnot.
百叶窗是新的  全都粉刷一新
Well, the blinds are new. Everything's been painted.
天啊
Jesus.
设施齐全
Utilities are included.
折叠式的  太好了
Stacking. Sweet.
-有有线电视吗  -已经装了天线了
- You got cable? - Already wired.
打个电话就能开通  很快捷
Just call to activate. High speed, whatever.
浴室  瓷砖很酷
Bathroom, cool tile.
卧室
Bedroom.
很棒
Nice.
我很喜欢硬木地板
I'm a fan of the hardwood.
这么说  你有兴趣
So? You're interested?
毫无疑问
Definitely.
那你也接受NPNS
And you're good with NPNS?
对不起  你说什么
Sorry. What?
广告上说的  不准吸烟  不准养宠物
In the ad? No smoking, no pets.
你要吸烟就到外面去吸
You want to smoke, you do it outside.
-可以  不用担心  -按照惯例
- It's cool. No worries. - The usual drill.
W-2: 美国雇员必须填写的文件  包括年收入和缴纳的税
我要W-2表  最近的收入证明和雇主信息
I'll need a W-2 or a recent pay stub, current employer,
还有以前的地址什么的资料
Former address, you know, the yadda-yadda.
如果都没问题  我会打电话通知你
And if it's all copasetic, I'll call.
听我说
Look,
情况是  我可以
The thing is I can...
简直难以置信
Unbelievable.
最近我正处在过渡阶段
I'm currently in-between situations.
那我最近不准备出租
And I'm currently not renting.
我有钱  有能力付房租
I got the money and I'm totally good for it
一直都会有
For, like, ever.
别这样  唷  求你了
Come on, yo, can you please,
就当是帮帮兄弟吧
Please just help a brother out?
唷  我老爸可没这么好说话
Yo, my dad's not really a "make exceptions" kind of guy.
-相信我  -你老爸
- Trust me. - Your dad?
房子是我老爸的  我帮他打理
Owns the place. I manage it.
我要的是白纸黑字
Pen on paper, that's what I need.
否则你就到别的地方玩去
Or go run your game somewhere else.
别傻了  我无处可去了  这里就是我的家
Dude, I got nowhere else to go. This is it.
我真的没有骗你  相信我好吗
And I got no game, all right?
我只需要一个机会
I just need a chance.
我的家人把我赶了出来
Look, my folks, they kicked me out.
很明显  我不太长进
I'm a disappointment, apparently.
再一次让他们失望了
Didn't meet their expectations, again.
所以我现在  无家可归了
So, you know, now I'm "gratis" or whatever.
但是知道吗
But you know what?
我是个好人  工作努力
I'm a good person and I work hard.
我会每个月都准时付房租的
I will pay you every month and I will pay you on time.
我不会搞砸的  我发誓
I will not mess this up, okay? I swear.
现在租金涨价了
Rent just went up.
一个月多付一百
A hundred more a month.
那是现金价
That's the cash price.
你酷毙了  你不会后悔的
You rock. You won't regret this.
还有除了第一个和最后一个月
And, in addition to first and last,
我还想要你先多付两个月
I want two more months.
DBAA费用  恕不退款
DBAA fee, nonrefundable.
当然  DBAA  当然没问题
Of course. No problem. DBAA. Obviously.
什么是DBAA
What's DBAA?
-"别做讨厌的人"  -我懂了
- "Don't be an asshole." - Gotcha.
我就住在隔壁
I live next door.
真的吗
Really?
别以为你有权利霸占着房子
And don't think for one second you have squatters' rights,
它不属于你
Because you don't.
如果你搞砸了  你就得马上滚蛋
If you blow this, I want you gone.
我了解你们这些人  我会把你一脚踹出门
I know guys that'll have your skinny ass
然后把东西扔出去  你连眼睛都来不及眨
Out back by the dumpster faster than you can blink.
我会帮你搞定这些  签名就行
I'll fill it in. Just sign your name.
顺便问问  你叫什么
Which is what, by the way?
杰西
It's Jesse.
杰西·杰克逊
Jesse Jackson.
真的吗
Seriously?
怎么了
What?
-你在干什么  -享受生活  还能干什么
- What are you doing? - Beating off. What's it look like?
我看到的确实是这样
That is, in fact, exactly what it looks like to me.
酿酒是一种艺术  玛丽
Brewing is an art form, Marie.
希望你也能懂得欣赏
I think you'd appreciate that by now.
这可是06年圣诞节的一批  快尝尝
Christmas, the batch of '06? Come on.
好吧  我直说吧
So, let me get this straight.
你居然请了病假躲在这里
You call in sick the day after receiving
还是在得到了梦寐以求的升职以后
A long-awaited career-boosting promotion
就为了在这里喝酒寻开心
So you can play October fest in your man cave?
我真的不明白  不懂
I don't get it. Really, I don't.
宝贝儿  放松点
Babe, relax.
别让我放松
Please, don't tell me to relax.
-你知道我讨厌听到这话  -没错
- You know I hate that. - Right.
戴夫说我应该说出来
Dave said I should express that.
我想说的是一切都很好
All I'm saying is everything's fine.
我就想放天假
I can take a day.
没什么大不了的
No big deal.
现在  我可爱的小宝贝儿快走吧
Now, get that sweet ass out of here
不然我没法集中精力
So I can concentrate.
好吧  计划是什么
Okay, so what's the plan?
计划就是我们制毒
The plan is we cook.
我们为什么还要制毒
Why are we cooking
现在根本卖不出去
When we can't even move what we cook?
你觉得靠你自己能卖出去多少
Well, how much do you think you can sell on your own?
假设我白天制毒  你晚上去卖的话
Say if I cooked during the days and you worked the nights.
-傻瓜  -什么
- Dude. - What?
在屠库之前  那不是你的想法吗
Prior to Tuco, that was your plan, wasn't it?
我知道这比我们之前赚的少多了
I understand it'll be a fraction of what we brought in before,
但我们还有别的选择吗
But still, what choice do we have?
首先  别说什么我们
First of all, there's no "we."
你说的是我  一个人单干
You're talking me, solo,
在外面苦干还要担心吃子弹
Busting hump slinging shards.
我现在有案底了
I got profile now.
你不懂吗  有个禁毒署的家伙盯上我了
Don't you get that? A D.E.A.'s up my ass.
我可不会为了那点小钱
I'm not exposing myself
把自己暴露了
to that level of risk for chump change.
-没门  -那你想怎么样
- No way. - Then what do you suggest?
我想我们谁
I don't think either of us are eager
都不会再想和屠库这样的家伙合作了
to jump into bed with another Tuco.
我现在有经济压力
I got bills, man.
你会有经济负担
You've got bills?
房租  唷  有责任了
Rent, yo. Responsibilities.
我失去的远比得到的多
I've already lost more than I have made,
我厌倦了整天在这儿胡搞乱来的日子
And I am tired of dicking around out here.
想知道我失去了多少吗
You want to know how much I've got left?
我第一轮的治疗结束了以后
After completing my first round of treatment
为世界上最贵的不在场证明买单
And financing the world's most expensive alibi?
什么都没了  都没了
Zero! Zip! Nothing!
之前的一切都付诸东流
I've got nothing to show for all of this.
一分钱都没能留给家人
Nothing for my family, which,
要是你还记得的话  那才是该死的重点
As you might remember, was the damn point!
但是现在认输并不是好主意
But seeing as throwing in the towel is not an option,
现在只有两条路可选
That leaves us with a total of two choices.
要么再和另一个杀人疯子做生意
We go into business with yet another homicidal lunatic
要么你和我开始
Or you and I start...
你尽你所能卖货
You selling whatever you can.
还有第三种选择
There's a third way.
是什么
And what would that be?
我们自己做屠库
We got to be Tuco.
省掉中间商  我们自己做经销
Cut out the middle man. Run our own game.
那你要怎么做
So you're going to, what?
用把猎刀把病毒吸进鼻子吗
Snort meth off a bowie knife?
把反对你的人都往死里打
You gonna beat your homies to death when they dis you?
听我说  我认识几个人
Look, I know some guys. All right?
我可以建立销售网络
I can create a network.
我们自己控制生产和分销
We control production and distribution.
我们从第一线退下来
That way, we stay off the front lines
不要自己去冒险
while moving some serious glass.
关键是能赚钱  对吗
The point here is to make money, right?
赚大把大把的钱
Sky-high stacks.
-难道我说的不对吗  -不是我不想这么干
- That's not the point? - No, I am not willing to do that.
谁说那关你的事了
Who said anything about you?
我不同意这个计划
I don't vote for this plan.
我不喜欢不认识的人加入我们的生意
I'm not comfortable bringing in unknown enties into our operation.
你没有投票的权利
You don't get to vote.
你再说一遍
I beg your pardon?
我们可是合作伙伴  记得吗
This is a partnership, remember?
我记得
I remember.
你制毒  我卖毒
You cook, I sell.
我们一开始就是这么分工的
That was the division of labor when we started all this.
现在也该这么保持下去
And that's exactly how we should have kept it.
这样我肯定不会让自己被锁在卡车里
'Cause I sure as hell didn't find myself locked in a trunk
还要被抢指着跪在地上等死
or on my knees with a gun to my head
在你这贪婪的老头来之前都不会
Before your greedy old ass came along, all right?
好吧  我承认还要学着慢慢来
All right, I will admit to a bit of a learning curve.
可能我是太有野心了
And perhaps I was overly ambitious.
但无论如何  不会再发生了
But in any case, it's not gonna happen that way anymore.
非常正确  知道为什么吗
Damn straight. Know why?
因为我们这次按我的办法来
'Cause we do things my way this time,
否则我就不干了
or I walk.
你现在更需要我
You need me more than I need you.
沃尔特
Walt.
唷  瘦子皮特  最近怎么样
Yo, Skinny Pete. What's up, brother?
康宝  见到你真好
Eh, Combo. Good to see you.
欢迎光临寒舍
Welcome to my humble abode.
房子不错啊  伙计
Good deal, mover. Good deal.
唷  猴子
Yo. Badger, hey.
房子真酷啊  伙计
Cool crib, man.
还有回声
It echoes.
我带你们虚拟地参观一下
Let me give you a virtual tour.
等离子彩电会挂在这里
Plasma is gonna go right here.
可能50英寸  壁挂式
Probably, like, a 50-inch wall-mounted.
等离子比液晶的牛多了  唷
Plasma rocks it over LCD, yo.
才不  会烧屏的  唷
Nah. They burn in, yo.
但图画质好多了  黑色也很纯
But the picture's way sharper. Blacks are deeper, too.
马上三维电视机也要有了
They got 3-D coming out, like, any day now.
那才是我想要的
That's what I'm waiting for.
-A片  爽啊  -老天啊
- Porn, cuz! - Jesus.
那可是三维立体的  感觉就在眼前
Like, 3-D ta-tas, like, right in your face.
我还要弄几个
I'm gonna get a couple of
零重力椅子放在这里
Those zero-gravity chairs for right here,
终极的观看享受
For your ultimate viewing comfort.
那可得花大价钱
Those are buck.
这里要弄得空旷些
It's gonna be pretty much sparse.
亚洲现代风格
Very Asian-y, modern stuff.
风水  唷  我懂一些
Feng shui, yo. I can dig it.
我想放几支蜡烛
And I'm thinking, just a bunch of candles,
在这里弄个小喷泉什么的
Maybe one of those little fountain jobs right here.
肯定会超酷
It's gonna be chill.
女士们就喜欢搞那些烛光情调
The ladies, they cream up real nice for, like, candles and shit.
你肯定会艳福不浅啊
You are going to score, big time!
我们坐下来谈谈正事怎么样
All right, so how about we get, you know, down to it?
你们想吃的话  有点零食饮料
There's some refreshments over here if you want to partake.
还有别的什么吗
You got any other refreshments?
我已经戒了  有一阵子了
I could kick it. It's been a while.
我现在就想尝一口
I could totally go for a loving spoonful.
今天没有啤酒  也没有大麻
No bomb, no beer, no weed.
要抽自己回家抽
You smoke it up on your own time.
在这里只谈正事
We're talking business here.
听好了  现在这么干
So listen up. This is how it goes.
我给你们每人一盎司货
I front each of you an ounce.
你们卖2500我拿2000你们拿500
You sell it for 2,500. I keep the two, you keep the five.
别揩油  老老实实卖  懂吗
No cutting it. You sell it as is, all right?
2500一盎司
2,500 an ounce?
价钱有点好像太高了
That's kinda, like, hopeful, bro.
街上都只卖1700  1800
Street's maybe 17, 18.
这可是最上乘的货
This is the best shiz ever.
阿爹阿娘都会想要尝尝
Everybody and their mother's gonna want a taste.
还有  现在还有谁在卖货
And second, who else is selling right now, huh?
-外面确实断货了  -大家都去教堂了
- It's dry out there, that's for sure. - Church.
所以重点是你们想怎样
So you point it how you want, okay?
男女老少随便怎么来
Quarter, half, teener, whatever.
但是我要保证我那份2000  没得商量
But I make what I make. Two large. No exceptions.
少了我的  你就给我走人
Short me, you're out.
揩油  也给我走人
Cut it, you're out.
而且要快
Period.
我给你们的可是大好的赚钱机会
This is a big opportunity I am giving you.
听懂了吗
Understand?
猴子  怎么样
Badger, what is this?
大好机会
A big opportunity.
说的没错  这只是第一步
Exactly. All right? This is the ground floor.
兄弟们  能走多远要靠你们了
Gentlemen, how far you go is up to you.
那拿货出来吧  唷
So bring out the product, yo.
不在这儿  以后也不在这儿
Not here, all right? Not ever.
直接出货  我会告诉你们地点时间
Blind drop. I will let you know when and where.
好吗
All right?
我会通知你们
You'll be hearing from me.
现在我有大量的货要出手
Now, I got mad volume,
卖得越快  赚的也越多
So you move it quick, you move it right.
我的货源源不断
There is always more.
别做讨厌的人  生意开张了
DBAA, mo-fos.
你们加油干
All right? Apply yourselves.
那就是个龌龊的角落
It's an armpit.
不是龌龊的角落
It's not an armpit.
对不起  你说得对
Excuse me. You're right.
那里是西南方的巴黎之城
It's the Paris of the Southwest.
看在上帝的份上  那可是德克萨斯啊
Please, it's Texas, for God's sake.
就在没有王法的墨西哥边境上
Right on the border of lawless Mexican hell.
人头  他们会在那里扔人头
Human heads, they leave.
大毒枭们  会在那里抛尸
The cartels, they litter the place with human heads.
这就是派我去那里的原因
Pretty sure that's why I'm going there.
好像还应该大肆宣传庆祝一样
It's like a calling card or a shout-out or something.
要是华盛顿的话  我还能跟着一起去
Now, D.C., on the other hand, I could get behind.
你在那里埋头苦干
You just do your time like a good boy,
没几年就能在乔治城可爱的公寓大厦
And I could see us in a cute little condo in Georgetown
住上了
in a couple of years.
我上网
I went online
看了超棒的
To this fantastic
华盛顿地产网站
real estate website for D.C.
我说不清  好像那里很有
There's just so much, I don't know,
文化气息
culture there.
我和汉克上司的妻子梅琳达谈过
I was talking to Melinda, Hank's boss's wife.
那个留着钢盔头  永远画着唇线的女人
The one with the helmet hair and the permanent lip liner.
总之  她对我说
Anyway, she was saying that...
道歉吧
Apologize.
什么
What?
我不想
I will not listen
再多听一个字
To one more word
除非你先道歉
Until you apologize.
为了什么
For?
你心里清楚着呢  玛丽
You know perfectly well, Marie.
-很明显  我完全  -你撒谎了
- Well, obviously I don't... - Your lies.
对我说谎了
to me.
在商店里顺手牵羊
The shoplifting?
所有的一切
All of it?
难道你真的以为
Did you really think it was all just
这一切都能就这样算了吗
neatly gonna go away?
如果不是你硬要还回去的话
If you hadn't tried to return it...
道歉
Apologize.
这是你最后的机会  我是认真的
Now or never. I mean it.
否则我们就一刀两断
Or it'll never be the same.
为什么这样惩罚我
Why are you punishing me?
如果你完全不尊重我
If you don't respect me
不想道歉的话  那就告诉我实话
Enough to apologize, to tell me the truth, then...
我想找回以前的妹妹
I need my sister back.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你想要听血淋淋的细节吗
You want the gory details?
不  你不会想听的
No, you don't.
会让你睡不着的
Keep you up at night.
那么
So...
当时吓人吗
Was it scary?
非常恐怖  年轻人
Hell, yeah, it was freaking scary, you little punk.
老天啊
Jesus.
但你开枪比他快
But you were way faster than him.
我还在这里  不是吗
Well, I'm here, aren't I?
你揍扁他  还出名了
Hell, yeah. Kick ass and take names.
-儿子  -不用  没事
- Son. - Nah, it's fine.
你知道是什么感觉吗
You know what it is?
一个蟑螂从冰箱底下爬出来  你怎么办
A cockroach comes out from under a fridge, what do you do?
你根本不用想
I mean, you don't think about it.
你会打死它们
You stop them down.
他们怎么会变成那样
Where do they come from?
我是说罪犯  像你打死的那个
Criminals, like the one you...
你觉得是什么原因让他们变成了罪犯
What do you think it is that makes them who they are.
伙计  你最好问我关于蟑螂的问题
Buddy, you might as well be asking me about the roaches.
我所知道的就是有一大群的罪犯
All I know is there's a whole armada.
伙计  我去撒个尿
Man, I gotta piss like a racehorse.
警察
Cops!
我不肯定是你
I wasn't sure it was you.
新车吗
New car?
东西放在厢式车上了
Keeping things on the D.L.
我猜你的办法不奏效吧
I'm guessing this one doesn't bounce.
你那份
Your half.
15000  我承诺过的
15K. That's what I'm talking about.
不用客气
You're welcome.
上帝啊
Jesus.
帮我做做算术  好吗
Help me understand the math, okay?
我给了你一磅  对吗
I gave you 1 pound, correct?
每盎司  你和我平分2000
You and I split $2,000 per ounce.
每人1000  1磅也就是16盎司
$1,000 each. 1 pound, that's 16 ounces.
16盎司应该是16000才对
16 ounces should net to me $16,000.
是16
16,
不是15
Not 15.
出了点状况
Something came up.
出了状况
Something came up?
我的一个人被一帮吸毒的困住了
One of my guys got held up by a couple junkies.
损失了一盎司  但还好瘦子皮特没事
Lost an ounce. But it's cool, okay? Skinny Pete's cool.
所以你的意思是
So you're saying that
你的人被抢劫了  或者说  你被抢劫了
Your guy got robbed. Or, rather, you got robbed,
但是没关系
But it doesn't matter.
傻瓜  那个叫损耗
Dude, it's called "breakage," okay?
就像大超市  货品总会有损耗
Like K-Mart. Shit breaks.
而且你觉得这些都可以接受
And you're thinking this is acceptable?
这就是做生意的代价  唷
It's the cost of business, yo.
你要为了1000块跟我烦吗
You're sweating me over a grand?
我只是个化学家
Look, I'm just the chemist, here.
我可不是街上的小混混  唷
I'm not the street guy, yo.
对我来说你所谓的损耗
But it seems to me that what you call "breakage"
只是让自己看起来像傻子
Is just you making a fool of yourself.
我还要送你另一个专业术语
I've got another technical term for you.
不可持续的商业模式
"Non-sustainable business model."
你只看到了负面
You're focusing on the negative.
我们每天赚6000块  你还有什么问题
Six grand a day we're making. What's your problem?
消息泄露了怎么办
What happens when word gets out,
你雇的小丑可不会小心谨慎
And it's open season on these clowns you've hired?
一旦每个人都知道了杰西·平克曼
Once everyone knows that Jesse Pinkman,
大毒枭  被打劫了也不出声
Drug lord, can be robbed with impunity...
伙计  算了吧
Man, come on.
你以为屠库那样的人会有损耗吗
You think Tuco had breakage?
他确实会有  他会打断别人的骨头
I guess it's true, he did. He broke bones.
他会把在他地盘撒野的人头都拧碎
He broke the skull of anybody who tried to rip him off.
你还想要1000吗  是不是
You want another grand? Is that it?
-不是我想要说的  -拿着  给
- Not my point. - Take it. Here.
你现在有15000  昨天你还什么都没有
Look, you got 15,000 you didn't have yesterday.
我们在赚钱  总会有些情况
We're making bank. Shit happens.
我的人知道要怎么做  他们非常小心
My guys get what they're up against, and they're careful.
我也一样
So am I.
你就坐在家里好吃好喝共享天伦吧
And you're all tucked in at night with your precious family.
别再像怪人一样想这想那了
So why don't you just stop being such a freak about everything?
你的分工非常明确
You've made the division of labor very clear.
唷  说真的
Yo, I mean, seriously.
你到底想我怎么样
What the hell do you want me to do?
对不起
Sorry.
你溜进来了
You snuck in.
我都不知道你回家了
Didn't even know you were home.
你在吃什么
What you eating?
三明治  想吃的话冰箱里还有一个
A panini. There's another one in the freezer if you want it.
我以为我们从不吃那些东西
I thought we nixed those, huh?
我是说  那些不是低钠的吧
Yeah. I mean, aren't those the ones with the off-the-chart sodium?
我突然很想吃
I had a craving.
难得吃一次没什么大不了的
Once in a while is no big deal.
小沃尔特去哪里了
So where's Junior?
出去了
Out.
和谁
With whom?
去哪里了
Out where?
某个地方吧  我不知道
Somewhere. I don't know.
晚上9点之前会回来
He'll be back by 9:00.
我还以为你会对儿子的去向有所了解
I just thought you might have a clue where your son is.
那你为什么不知道
Why don't you?
为什么总是我一个人来关心他去哪里
Why am I the only one who needs to keep track of our son?
告诉你  沃尔特  你想知道就自己去问
I'll tell you what, Walt. You want to know where he is, ask him.
像我一样打电话给他
Just pick up the phone like I do.
可能你会知道
Perhaps you might know something...
这个
About this.
可能
Perhaps.
但也可能
And then again,
我不知道  沃尔特
Perhaps I don't, Walt
可能我梦游时抽过
Perhaps I smoked them in a fugue state.
我想要你解释一下
I'd like an explanation.
-你不会想再说下去  -你为什么要抽烟
- You really don't want to go down... - Why would you do this?
看在上帝的份上  你还怀着孕
You're pregnant, for God's sakes.
三根半香烟
Three and a half cigarettes
不会对孩子怎么样的
is not going to do a thing to the baby.
-不会怎么样的  -很高兴你这么肯定  医生
- Nothing. - I'm glad you're so sure, Doctor.
三根半  就这么多  剩下的都扔了
Three and a half. That was it. I tossed the rest.
你肯定很想听到这个
And I'm sure you'll be very glad to hear that, yes,
没错  我感到羞耻
Yes, I feel ashamed.
斯凯勒  做这样的事
Skyler, This is something that...
-一点都不像你  -真的吗
- This is so unlike you. - Oh, really?
你怎么会知道
How would you know?
不用  谢谢
No, thank you.
你问我想要你怎么做
You had asked me what I want you to do.
我想你把这个处理掉
I want you to handle it.